<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Instructions for the commissioners of the militia of the county of [blank] concerning giving license to some of the Scotish nation to remain in England.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Council of State.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1650</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A87280</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I246</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason 669.f.15[49]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R211985</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99870647</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99870647</idno>
            <idno type="VID">163123</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A87280)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 163123)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 246:669f15[49])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Instructions for the commissioners of the militia of the county of [blank] concerning giving license to some of the Scotish nation to remain in England.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Council of State.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1650]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed at end: Signed in the name, and by order of the Councel of State appointed by authority of Parliament.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "August. 21th 1650".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:163123:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>Inſtructions for the Commiſsioners of the <hi>Militia</hi> for the County of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> concerning giving Licenſe to ſome of the <hi>Scotiſh</hi> Nation to remain in <hi>England.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>VVHereas by a late Act of Parliament, Entituled, <hi>An Act to prohibit all Commerce and Traffique between</hi> England <hi>and</hi> Scotland, <hi>and Enjoyning the Departure of</hi> Scots <hi>out of this Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wonwealth,</hi> herewith ſent, all thoſe of the Scotiſh Nation are forbid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den to continue in <hi>England,</hi> under the penalties therein expreſſed, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs permitted ſo to do by the Parliament or Councel of State, as by the ſaid Act appeareth: And whereas there may be divers of that Nation now in <hi>England,</hi> that are of good and peaceable Behavior, and from whom there is no cauſe to fear that evil which the ſaid Act intends to prevent, yet will be by the ſaid Act in danger to be proceeded againſt as is thereby directed: And for that it would be a great trouble to the Councel, and a charge to the perſons, to make their perſonal Application to the Councel from all parts of the Commonwealth; The Councel, in purſuance of the Power given unto them, have thought fit to commit unto your care, the permitting of ſuch of the Scotiſh Nation to continue here, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> under the following Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lifications:</p>
            <p>ALl ſuch as having Families, do exerciſe any Trade or Manufacture, or that are Servants or Apprentices, and have reſided in <hi>England</hi> before and ever ſince the Scotiſh Invaſion in the year 1648, and have not been, nor are Delinquents, or under Sequeſtration by any Act or Ordinance of Parliament, nor Soldiers of Fortune, nor have mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſted their diſaffection to the Parliament and preſent Government.</p>
            <p>You are hereby authorized to give Licenſe to theſe to ſtay in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> (if they deſire it of you) for ſo long onely as until the Parliament or Councel of State ſhall give Order to the contrary: The Names of which perſons, with their Dwelling, are to be Entred into a Book by you to be provided for that purpoſe.</p>
            <p>The perſons thus to be Licenſed by you, are to take and Subſcribe the Engagement appointed by Authority of Parliament; and alſo ſhall before ſome of you who are Juſtices of the Peace, enter into Recog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizance <hi>Cuſtodibus Libertatis, &amp;c.</hi> in ſome convenient Sum not under Two hundred pounds, and ſo upward, according to the quality of the perſons, which is left to your judgement; conditioned, That they ſhall act nothing to the prejudice of this Commonwealth and preſent Government: And ſhall (within ſuch time after Summon left at their
<pb facs="tcp:163123:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>houſes, as you ſhall judge ſufficient for their journey, according to the diſtance of their dwelling hence, which we leave to you to determine and expreſs) make their appearance before the Parliament or the Councel of State, as they ſhall be by the ſaid Summons appointed; Their Subſcriptions of the Engagement, and Recognizances, you ſhall cauſe to be Regiſtred as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>You ſhall cauſe enquiry to be made after ſuch of the Scotiſh Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion as ſhall continue in your County, and are not qualified as above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, and that have not your Licenſe thereupon, and cauſe them to be proſecuted and proceeded againſt according to the ſaid Act.</p>
            <p>You are before the Firſt of <hi>October,</hi> to certifie to us all your pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings upon theſe Inſtructions, The Names of the perſons Licenſed, with their Subſcriptions and Recognizances: And if you meet with any particular caſe that is not clearly enough provided for by the ſaid Act or theſe Inſtructions, worthy of conſideration, You are to ſigni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie the ſame to us for further direction.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Signed in the Name, and by Order of the Councel of State Appointed by Authority of Parliament,</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
